本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
暂停营业
维修中
我刚刚没用手就吃了一大袋儿芝士条
I just ate a bag of cheese boodles without using my hands.
懒懒的周二呀  你还真是把这慵懒的力量传递给我了呢
Lazy Tuesday, you are delivering in a big way.
没错  终于可以过
Yeah, it's nice to finally have a day
任何奇怪的事情都没有发生的一天
where nothing interesting happens whatsoever.
大家快趴下
Everyone get down!
别让他尝到人类的血肉
Don't let it taste human flesh.
-这是什么东西  -我们能收养吗
- What is it? - Can we keep it?
杀了它  快杀了它
Kill it, kill it!
要有耐心
Patience.
抓到你了
Gotcha!
太好了  现在把它弄出去
Great. Now get it outta here.
闻起来就像是死神的呕吐物
Smells like if death could barf.
阿福叔公  需要我帮什么忙吗
Grunkle Ford, need any help with that?
我读过你日志里介绍的每一种生物
I've read all about these creatures in your journal,
-我觉得  -不可以
- and I think I-- - No!
很抱歉  迪普
I'm sorry, Dipper.
我走的这条黑暗  怪诞的道路
On the dark, weird road I travel,
恐怕不能让你跟来
I'm afraid you cannot follow.
好啦  晚饭的时候叫我哦
Well, call me for dinner.
那下次可以吗  不可以吗
Maybe next time then? Or not.
或许永远都不可以
Or never.
哦  迪普  不要太在意了
Oh, Dipper, don't take it so hard.
不  还是在意一点吧
No, do take it hard.
认真地在意一下这件事情
Take it hard and serious.
我的兄弟是个危险的百事通
My brother is a dangerous know-it-all
他正在搞的那些实验更是危险
and the stuff he's messing with is even worse.
为了你自己好  不要跟他走得太近  听见了吗
Do yourself a favor and stay away from him, you hear me?
但是  斯坦叔公  整个夏天
But Grunkle Stan, all summer long,
我都一直想知道这本日志的作者是谁
I've wanted to know who the author of the journal was.
现在那个人就住在我们的地下室里
Now the guy lives in our basement,
而我却不能跟他说话
and I can't even talk to him.
就别操心地下室里的事情了
Don't worry about what's on the basement.
-你属于地上  跟我和梅宝在一起  -是呀
- You belong up here with me and Mabel. - Yeah!
再说  《神探福尔摩鸭》周五播出这季最后一集
Besides, the season finale of <i>Duck-tective</i> is Friday.
这周能揭开这个谜团就已经足够了
That's all the mystery you need this week.
来吧  迪普  和我们一起学鸭子叫吧
Come on, quack with us, Dipper.
嘎嘎嘎
Quack, quack, quack.
对  嘎嘎嘎
Yeah. Quack, quack, quack.
嘎嘎嘎
Quack, quack, quack!
他怎么不叫啊
Why isn't he quacking?
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： WaitinZ
翻译： Baker  peace  阿拱
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第二季第十三集
Gravity Falls  S02E13  Dungeons Dungeons and More Dungeons
亲爱的爸爸妈妈
Dear Mom and Dad,
我们在重力泉已经几个月了
we've been in Gravity Falls for a few months,
发生了很多事情
and so much has happened.
就在昨天  重力反转了
Just yesterday, gravity reversed itself,
宇宙差点都给毁灭了
almost destroyed the universe,
整个小镇被完全毁坏了
and totally wrecking the whole town.
他们说是地震所致
<i>They say it was an earthquake,</i>
当地服务员
但是你知道我是怎么想的吗
<i>but you know what I think?</i>
我打算开始供应
<i>I think I'm gonna have to start serving</i>
大头朝上的菠萝蛋糕
<i>pineapple right-side up cake.</i>
对不对啊
<i>Am I right?</i>
到底  对不对啊
毕市长
现在就让我们开始重建小镇吧
<i>Let the rebuilding of the town begin.</i>
拆迁球  开始拆迁吧
<i>Wrecking ball, start wrecking things.</i>
电视台
这个夏天最酷的事
The coolest part of the summer
就是传送门里走出了斯坦叔公的孪生兄弟
was Grunkle Stan's twin brother came out of this portal thingy
没想到叔公还能买一送一
Now we have two grunkles for the price of one.
他们在一起简直可爱极啦
And they are adorable together.
我们彼此相亲相爱
"We love each other so much!"
梅宝  你绝对猜不出我今天在商店里发现了什么
Mabel, you'll never guess what I found at the store today.
小狗  带着帽子的小狗
Dogs. Dogs with hats!
不  是我最喜欢的由幻想言语  等级计数
No. It's my favorite fantasy-talking, level-counting,
统计以及方格纸集于一体的游戏
statistics and graph-paper involving game of all time:
《满哪儿都是地下城》
Dungeons, Dungeons, and More Dungeons!
你想跟我玩吗
You wanna play it with me?
这个嘛  我确实挺喜欢独角兽的
Well, I do like unicorns,
还有那个帅气的精灵看起来挺有意思的
and that hot elf looks promising.
-这游戏怎么玩  -规则挺简单的
- How do you play? - The rules are simple.
首先  通过摇一个三十八面的骰子
First, you roll a 38-sided die
来确定每个玩家的统计分析能量球等级
to determine the level of each player's statistical analysis power orb.
这些魔法球直接关系到你的队伍
These orbs relate directly to the amount of power quadrants
所支配的能量象限的数量
that your team has dominion over,
这与你的象限包中的反象限是成反比的
which is inverse to the anti-quadrants in your quadrant satchel.
然后我们会骑独角兽吗
And then we ride unicorns?
对
Yes!
也不对
And no.
首先  我们要画个图表
First, we make a graph.
这就像是游戏版的作业
This is like Homework the Game.
来嘛  梅宝  至少要有两个人才能玩这个游戏
Come on, Mabel. I need at least two people to play.
哦  天哪  快看哪
Oh, wow, would you look at that?
两个人
Two people.
嘿  苏斯  愿意跟我玩一会儿“三地下城”小游戏吗
Hey, Soos, up for a little game of D & D & More D?
抱歉  迪普  我对那些笔啊  纸啊的东西不感冒
Sorry, Dipper, I don't go in for that pen-and-paper kinda stuff.
-我更倾向于泡纸法角色扮演  -啥
- I'm more of an FCLORP-er. - A what?
泡纸法角色扮演
FCLORP.
泡沫和纸板为装备  合法的户外角色扮演游戏
Foam & Cardboard Legitimate Outdoor Role Playing.
在这个游戏里  一群工匠组成的激情兄弟会
It is where a passionate brethren of craftsmen
把他们的梦想带到魔幻的现实生活中
bring their dreams to magical reality.
放开那位女祭司  精灵法师
Let yon priestess go, Elf Mage.
休想  圣骑士
Never, Paladin Radmaster.
火球  火球  火球
Fireball, fireball, fireball.
我是个堡垒
I'm a fortress.
好吧  还是谢谢你了  苏斯
Well, thanks anyways, Soos.
天啊  这就是那个需要大量计算和写字
Say, is this that game that's mostly math and writing
封面上印的东西一个也没有的游戏吗
and isn't anything like the picture on the box?
对  就是它  你想跟我玩吗  斯坦叔公
Yes, it is! You wanna play with me, Grunkle Stan?
小子  听着  我宁愿在赌城摇骰子
Ha! Look, kid, I prefer to do my dice rolling in Vegas.
再说  只有书呆子设计出的游戏
Besides, only a game designed by nerds
才会把“魅力”当做幻想中的技能
would have "Charisma" as a fantasy power.
来看看这个
Check this out.
当面对彼方的敌人时
"When facing yon adversaries,
要自己掩护在精灵护盾下
shield thyself under an elfan buttress."
哈哈  再说一遍
Ha ha, say it again.
护臀
Buttress.
嘿  你们尽管笑吧
Hey, laugh all you want.
你们不过是智商不够看不懂而已
You guys just aren't smart enough to understand it.
抱歉啦  兄弟  但是这个的确有点呆
Sorry, dude, but it is kinda nerdy.
好了  我要去围攻一个地精要塞了
Well, I'm off to lay siege to a goblin fortress.
向我奶奶的后院进军
To my grandma's backyard!
真棒  你摇了个十七
Oh, nice, you rolled a 17.
这也太悲催了
And this is sad.
也许我还是重新迷恋温蒂比较好
Maybe I should start obsessing over Wendy again.
嘿  还给我
Hey, give it back.
快点  冈珀斯  快松嘴
Come on, Gompers. Let go.
哦天哪  我的三十八面骰子
Oh, man, my 38-sided die!
迪普  别动
Dipper, stop!
阿福叔公
Great-uncle Ford.
关于来地下室这事  我是怎么说的
What did I say about coming down here?
我的工作太过危险  活生生的灵魂承受不来
My work is far too dangerous for a single living soul
哪怕只有一秒钟
to spend even one second--
等一下  那是《满哪儿都是地下城》
Wait. Is that a 38-sided die
里的三十八面骰子吗
from Dungeons, Dungeons, And More Dungeons?
是的  你知道这个游戏
Yeah. You know that game?
笔与纸  剑与盾
With pen and paper, shield and sword...
我们的征途将成为最美的回报
...our quest shall be our sweet reward!
这是我在整个多元宇宙里最喜欢的游戏
This is my favorite game in the whole multi-verse.
实在不敢相信它还在生产
I can't believe they still make it.
的确是啊  我整天都在找人陪我玩
They do, and I've been looking all day for someone to play with me.
小子  你知道这意味着什么吗
My boy, do you know what this means?
我正在做的所有工作必须立即停止
We must stop everything I've been working on at once,
开玩喽
and play!
大概会留疤
That's going to leave a mark.
好的  我觉得我们已经做好万全准备
Ok. I think we've got everything we need to watch
就等明晚的《神探福尔摩鸭》大结局了
The season finale of <i>Duck-tective</i> tomorrow.
我甚至做了一个零食滑道
I even made mouth ramps
这样我们就可以把食物倒进嘴里
so we can pour food into our mouths
还不用把眼神离开屏幕
without taking our eyes off the screen.
我用多余的动物标本做了主人公模型
And I recreated the main character out of spare taxidermy parts.
嘎嘎  我是福尔摩鸭
Quack, quack, I'm the duck detective.
谁偷了我的面包
Who stole my bread loaf?
这简直太胡来了
That is so messed up.
迪普一定爱死
Dipper would love that.
是啊  话说那个小家伙跑到哪里去了
Yeah, where is the little squirt anyway?
我一下午都没看见他
I haven't seen him all afternoon.
好了  你走进了卧室
All right, you enter the chamber.
安塔贝拉公主向你眨眼示意
Princess Unattainabelle beckons you.
但等等  这是个陷阱
But wait, it's a trap.
是恼人的可能性大师创造的幻象
An illusion cast by Probabilitor the Annoying.
你知道他的弱点  对吗
You know his weakness, right?
最佳统计后的异常现象将超过37小于51
Prime statistical anomalies over 37 but not exceeding 51.
太棒了  打败你了
Yes! In your face,
你个纸糊的巫师
you cardboard wizard.
老巫师看起来和我玩的那会儿不太一样
Hmm, the old boy looks a bit different than he did back in my day.
对啊  他们每过几年都会更改一下画风
Yeah, they change the art every few years.
幸好  你没赶上
Thankfully, you missed the period
那段创始人想把游戏变得更酷的时期
when the creators of the game tried to make it "cooler."
天哪  这游戏真是无聊透顶
Man, this game is boring.
你们竟敢挑战可能性大师
You dare challenge Probabilitizzle?
把猫放回  摇起骰子
Put the cat back and roll the dice
不要妄想挑战巫师  因为巫师
Don't step to the wizard 'cause the wizard...
《尊严地下城与这这那那》已更新第九赛点
<i>Diggity Dungeons All & That updated for the nine double-deuce!</i>
-有酷游戏的地方就有我  -回见
<i>- Available wherever dope games are sold. - Peace!</i>
九十年代  真是黑暗的时代
Must've been dark times, those '90s.
幸好那时候我被困在时空夹缝里了
Sounds like a good time to be stuck between dimensions.
阿福叔公  我一直想问你
Great-uncle Ford, I've been meaning to ask you.
你从那台机器中出来之前都在哪里啊
Where were you before you came out of that machine,
你在里面又干了些什么呢
and what have you been doing down here?
你是不是在那帘子后面搞什么发明呢
Are you working on something behind that curtain?
迪普  你和你的家人最好不要插手这件事情
Dipper, it's best if you and the family stay away from that subject.
说实话  我不确定你们是否能接受实情
Honestly, I'm not sure any of you could handle the real answer.
但我能接受啊
But I could handle it.
但我能给你看一个我带回来的小玩意儿
But I can show you a little something I brought back with me.
无穷面骰子
An infinity-sided die.
太酷了  太不可思议了
That's so cool... and impossible.
这东西在九千个时空中都是违禁品
These things are outlawed in 9,000 dimensions.
想知道为什么吗  看看这些标识
Wanna know why? Look at those symbols.
无穷面就意味着无穷种结果
Infinite sides means infinite outcomes.
如果我掷它  什么都有可能发生
If I rolled it, anything could happen.
我们的脸可能会融化成果冻
Our faces could melt into jelly.
世界可能会变成一只鸡蛋
The world could turn into an egg.
或者只是掷出数字八  没人能知道结果
Or you could just roll an eight. Who knows?
所以我把它保存在这个廉价塑料盒里
That's why I have to keep it in this protective cheap plastic case.
现在  回到游戏
Now, back to the game.
可能性大师的处境岌岌可危
You've got Probabilitor on the ropes.
天哪
Oh, man.
然后如果我把它拉到这儿  再加上三
Then if I drag it here, and then a plus-three--
迪普  你到底睡不睡觉
Dipper, are you gonna go to sleep?
你已经说蠢话说了好几个小时了
You've been saying dork words for hours.
抱歉  梅宝  我必须完成这个地下城
Sorry, Mabel. I gotta finish this dungeon.
明天绝对能击败阿福叔公
It's gonna totally stump Great-uncle Ford tomorrow.
我等不及想看他脸上的表情了
I can't wait to see the look on his face.
你  呃  最近经常和阿福呆在一起  是不是啊
You're, uh, spending a lot of time with old Fordsie lately, huh?
你绝对想不到
You have no idea.
我早就知道作者会很酷
I knew the author must be cool,
而他甚至比我想象中的还要棒
but he's better than I imagined.
他也不会像你和斯坦叔公那样
And he doesn't make fun of me all the time,
一直嘲笑我
the way you and Grunkle Stan do.
再给他点时间
Give him time.
噢  好吧
Ah, you got me.
你说得对
You got me.
谢谢你今天过来一起看
Thanks for coming over to watch tonight's
《神探福尔摩鸭》的最终集  格兰达
<i>Duck-tective finale, Grenda.</i>
怎么会  我已经深深爱上这些鲜活的角色了
Of course. I'm so invested in the life of these characters.
嘿  嘿  瞧你呀
Hey, hey, look at you.
某些人还真是盛装打扮呢
Someone's all dressed up.
今天是个大日子
It's a big night.
我们都会铭记今晚
I think we all remember where we were
这个福尔摩鸭中枪身亡的夜晚
when we learned Duck-tective was shot.
各位  入座看剧
Viewing positions, everyone!
啊  方格纸  去死  去死
Ahh! Graph paper. Kill it, kill it!
迪普  你能不能换个房间玩
Dipper, could you maybe move this to another room?
不行
No dice.
地下室已经没地方了
We ran out of room in the basement
而且我们就要创造世界记录了
and we're going for a world record.
我掷
Now dice!
三十二
Thirty-two.
-好耶  七千点伤害  -算你厉害
- Yes! 7,000 points damage. - You got me.
为什么会这样
Why with this?
阿福  还想破什么记录
Wanna break a record, Ford?
你早就是世界上最书呆子的老头儿了
You already got it for world's nerdiest old man.
嘿  至少我不会穿着正装去看小孩子看的电视剧
Hey, at least I'm not all keyed up to watch a kids' show.
我告诉你 《神探福尔摩鸭》
I'll have you know that Duck-tective
有很多悬疑元素而且非常幽默
has a big mystery element, and a lot of humor
远超孩子的理解范围
that goes over kids' heads.
我并不能完全看懂
I don't get a lot of it,
但我喜欢拟人化的动物
but I like animals in human situation.
斯坦叔公  还有几分钟就要开始了
Grunkle Stan, it starts in a few minutes.
你动了就要付出代价
Move that and pay the price.
怎么  五十个魔法小矮人币
Oh, what, 50 magical dwarf dollars?
不要嘲笑我们奇幻的钱币系统
Don't mock our fantastical monetary system.
我想怎么嘲笑都行  这是我看电视的房间
I'll mock all I want. It's my TV room.
这是我的房子  你
It's my house! You...
听着  斯坦利  你就从来没想过
Listen, Stanley, did it ever occur to you
如果你加入我们  可能会体会到其中的乐趣吗
that if you joined us, you might actually have fun?
什么  你给我听好了
What? Now you listen to me.
只要我还活着  我就绝对
As long as I live, I will never--
-斯坦叔公  等等  -不会
- Grunkle Stan, wait. - Ever.
-斯坦利  -玩你那抖机灵的破游戏
- Stanley! - Play your smarty-pants nerd game.
不
No!
46'闪电时空的凡人们
Mortals of Dimension 46 Apostrophe Backflash.
跪在我脚下然后
Kneel before me and...
哭泣吧
Snivel.
我是可能性大师
I am Probabilitor,
所有神话中最伟大的巫师
the greatest wizard in all mathology,
可能会有0.4的小误差
give or take an error of 0.4.
这正常吗
Is this normal?
你是来赐予我们一次永生难忘的任务吗
Have you come to send us on the quest of a lifetime,
只因为我们是你见过的最聪明的玩家
because we're the smartest players you've ever met?
你们的确是我见过的最聪明的玩家
You are the smartest players I've ever met.
所以我要来吃掉你们的大脑
That's why I'm going to eat your brains,
获取你们的智慧
to gain your intelligence.
这就是我要做的
It's what I do.
-这是他的爱好  -啥
- It's his thing. - What?!
抓住他们
Seize them!
你的数学敌不过我的枪  笨蛋
Your math is no match for my gun, you idiot.
数学光波
Math ray!
我不是来玩游戏的
I'm not here to play games.
现在去树林完成终极游戏
Now to the forest for the ultimate game.
那么现在房间没人了
So the room's free now.
谁想看《神探福尔摩鸭》
Who wants to watch <i>Duck-tective?</i>
没人吗  格兰达霸占沙发咯
Nobody? More couch for Grenda.
噢  不  那个疯狂的巫师要
Oh, no. That crazy wizard is gonna eat
吃掉我们兄弟的脑子了  必须阻止他
our brother's brain. We have to stop him.
不如等他先咬几口阿福的脑子
Maybe let him get a couple of bites in Ford's brain first.
让聪明的智商变正常点儿
Even things out, smartness-wise.
-斯坦叔公  -好吧  好吧
- Grunkle Stan! - All right, all right.
既然没有其他选择
I guess if we have no other choice,
我们只能
we'll go on a...
踏上寻找巫师的史诗任务
epic wizard quest.
大家都拿好武器
Everyone grab a weapon.
好
Nice.
我们来救你了  迪普
We're coming for you, Dipper.
还有阿福叔公
And Great-uncle Ford.
还有那位帅气的精灵
And possibly that hot elf,
如果他跟这事有关系的话
if he's got anything to do with this.
我每吃一个大脑
With each brain I eat,
我的法术值都会增长
I shall increase my enchant-elligence.
如果我的手没被绑住
If my hands were free,
我就把你的脸撕碎
I'd break every part of your face.
时间到了
The time has come.
帅精灵  准备好煮脑锅
Hot elf, ready the brain-cooking pot.
呃  好  可能性大师
Uh, yes, Probabilitor.
我们一定很接近了
We must be getting close.
这些精灵的叮咬越来越频繁
These fairy bites are getting more frequent.
嘿  等等  听着
Hey, look, listen.
站住  你们这些闯入者非法踏入了
Halt! You interlopers are trespassing
可能性大师的古老树林
on the ancient forest of Probabilitor the wizard.
欲从此路过
If ye wish to pass,
要先完成七个超脱世俗的任务
first ye must complete seven unworldly quests,
一个比一个难
each more difficult than the last.
他死了吗
Is he... dead?
亲爱的  他有魔力  我保证他还好着呢
He's magic, sweetie. I'm sure he's fine.
森林里没有警察
There's no cops in the forest.
这个秘密我们要带到坟墓里
We take this to our graves.
-我们该怎么办  怎么办  -不要思考  迪普
- What do we do, what do we do? - Stop thinking, Dipper.
你大脑的褶皱越多
The more wrinkled your brain gets,
他就越想吃掉你的大脑
the more he'll wanna eat it.
现在有一个简单的数学问题
And now, a little math problem.
我把你们的大脑从脑袋里抽出来
When I subtract your brain from your skull,
撒上盐  拆散你们的家人  剩下的是什么
add salt and divide your family, what's the remainder?
你的屁股
Your butt!
什么  我的屁股可不是这个独特等式的组成元素
What? My butt isn't part of this particular equation.
见鬼  你们是怎么通过我唯一的护卫的
Drat! How did you make it past my one guard?
那好
Very well.
你们家人要救出你们只有一种办法
There's only one way your family can save you.
你们必须在《满哪儿都是地下城》游戏中打败我
You must defeat me in Dungeons, Dungeons, And More Dungeons,
真人游戏
real life edition!
什么  得了吧
What? Oh, come on.
我选择我的角色挑战
I choose my characters versus...
你们的角色
Yours.
我的耳朵
Oh, my ears.
变尖了
They're so pointy.
希望这束衣里面有护具
There better be something protective under this tunic.
噢不  没有
Oh, no, there isn't.
开玩笑吧
Seriously?
我们就不能比掰手腕或者其他什么的吗
Can't we just, like, arm wrestle or something?
来吧  这个游戏很好玩的
Come on, this game is a lot of fun.
我让妈妈给我带了午饭
I had my mom pack me a lunch.
苹果片  我最后再吃
Ew, apple slices? I'll eat you last.
制定规则吧  丑八怪
Just make with the rules, ugly.
游戏设定是一场战争对抗
The game is a battle royale.
我们通过掷骰子来施咒语帮助自己的角色
We help our characters by casting spells determined by rolls of the dice.
如果你们赢了  我就回到自己的时空
If you win, I go back to my own dimension.
但如果我赢了  我就会吃掉他们的大脑
But if I win, I eat their brains.
嘿  我不觉得这是个好
Hey, I'm not sure this is such a good--
-一言为定  -噢天哪
- Deal! - Oh, boy.
开始游戏吧
Let the game begin!
进攻
Attack!
我们该怎么做  接下来怎么走
What do we do? What are our moves?
没有固定的走法  由你来决定
There are no moves. You make them up.
什么  是那样吗
What? Really?
是的  我一直想告诉你
Yes. I tried to tell you.
这个游戏不仅需要数学知识  还需要冒险精神和想象力
This game involves math, but also risk and imagination.
-冒险精神  -想象力
- Risk! - Imagination?!
斯坦叔公  快想对策  就像说谎一样
Grunkle Stan, make something up. It's just like lying.
我出
I cast... uh...
防御盾牌咒
Shield of shielding.
我们成功啦
Ha! We're doin' it.
消除防御盾牌咒
Shield of shielding reversal spell.
我出欢乐时光弹力鞋
I cast giggle time bouncy boots.
烈火火焰剑
Fat flame-y sword.
超级炎热火焰剑
Super-hot flame-y sword!
不
No!
混蛋  你们永远别想逃得掉我的
Drat you. You'll never outrun my...
妖卷风  对就是字面意思
Ogre-nado. It is what it sounds like.
半人马牛怪
I cast Centaur-taur! Yah!
梅宝  我现在非常困惑又非常自豪
Mabel, I am so confused and so proud right now.
冲啊  迪普  上  你能行的
Go, go, go, Dipper! Go! You can do it!
好啊
Ha ha ha, yes!
最厉害的我留在最后出手
I was saving the worst for last.
噢不
Oh, no.
不可战胜兽
The impossi-beast.
我还以为他们禁了这个角色
Hey, I thought they banned this character.
话别说太早  我玩的可是
Think again. I'm playing
九一到九二年的争议版本
the controversial 1991-1992 edition.
我会想出对策武器的
I'll think of some weapons.
你不明白
You don't understand.
这是游戏中最厉害的怪兽
This is the most powerful monster in the game.
只有完美掷出38点才能打败它
He can only be defeated by rolling a perfect 38.
但能做到的概率是
But the odds of that are--
嘿  对于一个世界级赌鬼来说
Hey, long odds are what you want
不可能任务才是求之不得啊
when you're a world-class gambler.
好吧斯坦  你能做到
All right, Stan, you can do this.
爸爸需要一对
Papa needs a new pair of...
新双胞胎
twins!
不
No!!
抱歉  书呆子巫师
Sorry, nerd wizard.
你所有的智谋也比不上我这狗屎运
All of your smarts are no match for dumb luck.
死亡蛋糕咒
I cast Death Muffins!
太棒了
Yes!
就这样  游戏结束了
The game is, like, over.
精益求精  随便了
Excelsi-whatever.
不  我要回到原来的世界了
No! I'm returning to my own realm.
我正在变成纯粹的数学
I'm turning into pure math.
怎么会这样
What are the odds?!
斯坦叔公  真是太不可思议了
Grunkle Stan, that was amazing.
你怎么知道你一定会赢呢
How did you know that you would win?
嘿  赌鬼可不会揭露自己的秘密
Hey, a gambler never reveals his secrets.
天  无论八岁到八十  还是一百万岁
Man, that was fun for ages eight to 80.
不管你们多老  那游戏都能找到乐趣
Or a million or however old you guys are.
孩子  我很抱歉嘲笑你的游戏
You know, I'm sorry for making fun of your game, kiddo.
虽然这游戏对我来说可能太呆了
Sure, it might be too nerdy for me,
但是正合适你和我兄弟的怪里怪气
but it's just the right amount of nerdy for you and my brother.
如果你们俩想偶尔一起玩
And if you two wanna hang out sometimes,
我不会阻拦你们的
I won't get in your way.
说实话  经历了这些事
Actually, after all that,
我也想来点儿不那么用脑的乐趣了
I could use a little mindless fun.
伙计们  我们可以去看福尔摩鸭重播了
Guys, we can watch the second showing of <i>Duck-tective.</i>
现在还来得及
It's not too late.
我就要去往天空的大池塘了。
我搞不懂究竟是谁对你开的枪
<i>I just don't understand who shot you.</i>
足够聪明能打败侦探福尔摩鸭的只有
The only person clever enough <i>to defeat Duck-tective</i>
侦探福尔摩鸭
<i>is... Duck-tective.</i>
是时候做个了断…
双胞胎兄弟！
（恐惧地叫）
他一直有个双胞胎兄弟
He had a twin brother all along?
这就是我们苦苦等待的反转剧情么
That's the big twist we were waiting for?
都什么骗人的设定
What a rip-off.
唔  我大概一年前就预测到了
I predicted that, like, a year ago.
我把它放在这儿  你随时可以用
This will be here if you ever need it.
可以吗  我刚刚可让咱们陷入了游戏混乱啊
Really? Even though I got us into the whole game-playing mess?
咱俩都太痴迷了
Ah, we both got carried away.
看来咱们俩没有朋友的陪伴都会出岔子
I guess we'd both gone for a while without a friend.
迪普  我能告诉你一件事吗
Dipper, can I tell you something?
你之前问过我在忙什么
You asked me earlier what I was working on.
我在拆传送门
I dismantled the portal.
时空任意门对于门外的世界来说
An inter-dimensional gateway is too dangerous
实在太危险了
for the world it feeds into.
所以我知道斯坦用了它才那么生气
That's why I was mad at Stan for using it.
他救了我  可正如我所害怕的
He saved me, but as I feared,
不稳定的机器产生出了这个
the instability of the machine created this.
时空交际的裂痕
An inter-dimensional rift.
目前我还能控制
I've contained it for now,
但它非常非常危险
but it's incredibly dangerous.
迪普  我不希望你告诉其他人这件事
Dipper, I don't want you to tell anyone about this.
包括斯坦  甚至你姐姐也不行
Not Stan, not even your sister.
-你明白了吗  -我明白
- Do you understand? - Oh, of course.
我之前树了许多强大的敌人
In my time, I've made many powerful enemies.
不过我相信你会保守这个秘密
But I trust you with this secret.
现在去睡觉吧
Now get yourself to bed.
我还有很多研究要做
I have much research to do.
晚安  阿福叔公
Good night, Great-uncle Ford.
晚安  迪普
Good night, Dipper.
伙计们  你们觉不觉得咱们玩这个
Guys, do you ever think maybe we're doin' this
也许是因为自己的人生碌碌无为
'cause our lives aren't special enough?
所以靠幻想来逃避
That we use fantasy as an escape to avoid
咱们自我改善的需要
the self-improvement we all need?
也许我们应该出去走走  多和别人接触一下
That maybe we should just go out and grow with people?
堡垒不能说话  亲爱的
Fortresses can't speak, darling
我是个堡垒
I'm a fortress.
有人想救他吗
Does anyone wanna rescue him?
-我累了  -我就算了
- Ah, I'm tired. - I'm good.
漫长的一天
Long day.
不要妄想挑战巫师
Don't step to the wizard
因为巫师不是好惹哒
'cause the wizard don't play nice